https://mwswire.com/ccpa-privacy-statement/

MWS Wire Industries Privacy Notice for California Residents
Effective Date: June 1, 2019
This Privacy Notice for California Residents supplements the information contained in MWS WIRE INDUSTRIES Privacy Policy and applies solely to all visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of California (“customer” or “you”). We adopt this notice to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (CCPA) and any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this notice.
Information We Collect
The mwswire.com website (the “Site”) collects information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular customer or device (“personal information”). In particular, the Site has collected the following categories of personal information from its customers within the last 12 months:
CategoryExamplesCollected
IdentifiersA real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, Social Security number, driver's license number, passport number, or other similar IdentifiersYes
Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code
§ 1798.80(e.) ).A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver's license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. Yes
Protected Classification characteristics under California or federal lawAge (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information).No
Commercial InformationRecords of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendenciesYes
Biometric Information.Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identities or identifying information, such as, fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retinal scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data. No
Internet or other similar network activity.Browsing History, search history, information on a consumer's interaction with a website, application, or advertisement.Yes
Geolocation data.Physical locations or movementsYes
Sensory data.Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information.No
Professional or employment-related information. Current or past job history or performance evaluations.No
Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99) ).Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records. No
Inferences drawn from other personal information. Profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. No
Personal information does not include:
Publicly available information from government records.
Deidentified or aggregated consumer information.
Information excluded from the CCPA’s scope, like:
Health or medical information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA) or clinical trial data;
Personal information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FRCA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver’s Privacy Protection Act of 1994.
MWS Wire Industries obtains the categories of personal information listed above from the following categories of sources:
Directly from you. For example, from forms you complete or products and services you purchase.
Indirectly from you. For example, from observing your actions on our Site.
Use of Personal Information
We may use or disclose the personal information we collect for one or more of the following business purposes:
To fulfill or meet the reason you provided the information. For example, if you share your name and contact information to ask a question about our products or services, we will use that personal information to respond to your inquiry. If you provide your personal information to purchase a product or service, we will use that information to process your payment and facilitate delivery. We may also save your information to facilitate new product orders or process returns. If you submit a story about your experience with MWS Wire Industries, we may post that story on our Site, without identifying you by name or address.
To provide, support, personalize, and develop our Site, products, and services.
To create, maintain, customize, and secure your account with us.
To process your requests, purchases, transactions, and payments and prevent transactional fraud.
To provide you with support and to respond to your inquiries, including to investigate and address your concerns and monitor and improve our responses.
To personalize your Site experience.
For testing, research, analysis, and product development, including to develop and improve our Site, products, and services.
To respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or governmental regulations.
As described to you when collecting your personal information or as otherwise set forth in the CCPA.
MWS Wire Industries will not collect additional categories of personal information or use the personal information we collected for materially different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.
Sharing Personal Information
MWS Wire Industries may disclose your personal information to a third party for a business purpose. When we disclose personal information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract.
We share your personal information with the following categories of third parties:
Subsidiaries and affiliates.
Contractors and service providers.
Data aggregators.
Third parties with whom we partner to offer products and services to you.
Disclosures Of Personal Information For A Business Purpose
In the preceding 12 months, MWS Wire Industries has disclosed the following categories of personal information for a business purpose to the parties identified above:
Category A: Identifiers.
Category B: California Customer Records personal information categories.
Category C: Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.
Category D: Commercial information.
Category F: Internet or other similar network activity.
Category G: Geolocation data.
Sales Of Personal Information
In the preceding 12 months, MWS Wire Industries has not sold personal information.
Your Rights and Choices
The CCPA provides customers (California residents) with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and explains how to exercise those rights.
Access To Specific Information And Data Portability Rights
You have the right to request that MWS Wire Industries disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable customer request (see Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights), we will disclose to you:
The categories of personal information we collected about you.
The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.
Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that personal information.
The categories of third parties with whom we share that personal information.
The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).
If we sold or disclosed your personal information for a business purpose, two separate lists disclosing:
Sales, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient purchased; and
Disclosures for a business purpose, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient obtained.
Deletion Request Rights
Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another customer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 et. seq.).
Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information’s deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research’s achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with customer expectations based on your relationship with us.
Comply with a legal obligation.
Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.
Exercising Access, Data Portability, And Deletion Rights
To exercise the access, data portability, and deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable customer request to us by contacting us at:
MWS Wire Industries, Inc.                      or                    sales@mwswire.com
Attn: President
31200 Cedar Valley Drive
Westlake Village, CA 91362
Only you, or a person registered with the California Secretary of State that you authorize to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable customer request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable customer request on behalf of your minor child.
You may only make a verifiable customer request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period. The verifiable customer request must:
Provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative.
Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.
We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you.
Making a verifiable customer request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable customer request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.
Response Timing And Format
We endeavor to respond to a verifiable customer request within forty-five (45) days of its receipt. If we require more time (up to 90 days), we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing.
We will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.
Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding the verifiable customer request’s receipt. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily usable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance.
We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable customer request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.
Personal Information Sales Opt-out And Opt-in Rights
If you are 16 years of age or older, you have the right to direct us to not sell your personal information at any time (the “right to opt-out”). We do not sell the personal information of customers we actually know are less than 16 years of age, unless we receive affirmative authorization (the “right to opt-in”) from either the customer who is between 13 and 16 years of age, or the parent or guardian of a customer who is between 13 and 16 years of age. Customers who opt-in to personal information sales may opt-out of future sales at any time.
Non-Discrimination
We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not:
Deny you goods or services.
Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
Provide you a different level or quality of goods or services.
Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
However, we may offer you certain financial incentives permitted by the CCPA that can result in different prices, rates, or quality levels. Any CCPA-permitted financial incentive we offer will reasonably relate to your personal information’s value and contain written terms that describe the program’s material aspects. Participation in a financial incentive program requires your prior opt-in consent, which you may revoke at any time.
Other California Privacy Rights
California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits users of our Site that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please write or email to us at:
MWS Wire Industries, Inc.                      or                    sales@mwswire.com
Attn: President
31200 Cedar Valley Drive
Westlake Village, CA 91362
Changes To Our Privacy Notice
MWS Wire Industries reserves the right to amend this privacy notice at our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this privacy notice, we will post the updated notice on the Site and update the notice’s effective date. Your continued use of our Site following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.
Contact Information
If you have any questions or comments about this notice, the ways in which MWS Wire Industries collects and uses your information described below and in the Privacy Policy, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California law, please do not hesitate to contact us at:
MWS Wire Industries, Inc.                      or                    sales@mwswire.com
